AKBOR SHARIF

415-499-2364 sharifakbor7@gmail.com Berkeley, Ca <u>www.linkedin.com/in/sharifakbor7/</u> <u>www.github.com/AkborSharif</u>

ABOUT ME

Software engineer with deep experience in mobile/web development using Java, Javascript, NodeJs, Angular to uplift and drive excellence within the tech industry. Known for being an excellent problem solver, moving into projects with a high level of independence, and using knowledge to educate others.

EDUCATION HISTORY

University of California, Merced

BS in *Computer Science and Engineering* | Aug 2016 - May 2020

C-GPA: 3.59 & In-major GPA: 3.65

COURSES

- · Algorithm Design Analysis
- · Object-Oriented Programing
- Software Engineering
- · Database System with SQL
- Data Structure
- · Computer Architecture

TOOLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Hands-on Java Expertise
- Javascript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS
- Node.Js, AngularJS, Express, jQuery
- MongoDB, Mongoose, MySQL, Oracle
- Git, Github, Postman, Apache Tomcat Server
- EJS, JSP, JWT, JSON, Socket.io

LANGUAGES

- English
- Bangla
- Hindi

AWARDS

- Chancellor's List: Award given for GPA above 3.50
- Frances M Benton Scholarship: \$ 2000 awarded due to high GPA
- Innovate to Grow Mobile App Challenge: received a winning prize of \$500

WORK EXPERIENCE

CODING INSTRUCTOR

CodeFu: Coding for Kids, SF | Aug 2020 - Dec 2020

- Educating Python, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, and Java to elementary and high school kids
- Leading classes of a minimum of 10 kids to better understand basic fundamentals to problem-solving
- Younger kids are taught basic block programming through Scratch JR.

COMPUTER SCIENCE TUTOR

Bright Success Center, UC Merced | Oct 2019 - Sep 2020

- Main tutor for Java, Data Structures(C++), Algorithm
- Organized recurring review sessions for ~100 students
- Mentored students on tailoring class structure which helped build a solid foundation for success in their computer science degree

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

JAVA DEVELOPER AT TCS

Retail Bank Management System | Jan 2020 - Feb 2020

- Implemented an web application using Core Java, OracleDB, HTML, CSS, JSP
- Received hands-on experience on User Authentication, Rest API, Postman, JDBC, Apache Tomcat Server

FULL STACK DEVELOPER AT TCS

Media Application | Feb 2020 - March 2020

- Implemented a Media App using Node.js, Angular, MongoDB, RestApi, and JWT
- Used AngularJS for the frontend that provides a great user exerience
- Designed the backend with Node.Js, Mongoose, Express Framework that provides 100% Admin Authentication with JWT, and an easily manageable interface for the Admin.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Topcon Positioning System | Jan 2020 - May 2020

- Led a team of three engineers to create an award-winning app utilized by TopCon
- Developed a system that finds the Geolocation for difficult-to-reach targets based on two or more images captured
- Designed the algorithm using the standard triangulation method via GPS and IMU sensors and implemented it in android studio using Java, XML, Gradle, Mapbox API
- Created a free of cost, user friendly, and about 90% accurate positioning system without the use of any hardware

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Human-Computer Int. Lab UC Merced | Jan 2019 - Dec 2019

- Developed Android Input Method Editor (Keyboard) improving screen real-estate by 20% with superior typing experience
- Entry speed with the keyboard dropped at a much lower rate (26%)
 compared to google QWERTY (41%), indirectly suggesting the numbers
 and special symbols are easier to type with my gesture-based keyboard
- The research paper got accepted at the ISS2020 conference